# KÁROLY LÓNICH

Full-Stack Web Developer

00 36 302573633

karoly.lonich@smartcoder.dev

smartcoder.dev

Vác, Hungary

github.com/kal40

in linkedin.com/in/karolylonich

@KarolyLonich



I'm an innovative and technology driven professional with experience in JavaScript/React Node.is/Express.is SQL/MonogDB and seeking an entry-level remote software engineer position. During my 20 years electrical engineer professional career I've always enjoyed the programming and IT related tasks the most. I've learned that the end of the day the only thing that matters is results. I've decided to take a Full-Stack Web Development course and build some real applications. For the details and updates please see my website.

### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

**Full-Stack Developer** Freelancer | 2022 - Present

Taking the Full-Stack Web Development Program at CareerFoundry.

#### **Electrical and Control Senior Engineer**

Sherbiny Engineering | March 2018 - February 2022

Designed Electrical Control Panels and specified instrumentation mainly for Oil & Gas and Petrochemical industry for the Saudi Arabian market

• Commissioning support in Saudi Arabia.

#### **Gas Turbine Controls Project Engineer**

Baker & Hughs | June 2012 - March 2018

Led projects of Gas turbine control system upgrades and participated in couple of DCS contors upgrades. International projects in Energy and Oil & Gas industry around the world (with customers like Chevron, Linde, Sonatrach, Sonelgaz, EDF, Exxon, etc...)

- Migrated Mark IV and Mark V control systems to Mark VIe (GE latest technology). Integrated external systems like Excitation, Generator Control, Fire Protection Panel.
- Designed HMI and network topologies. Configured Programable Logic Controllers.
- Created Visual Basic macros for large data handling in Microsoft Excel.
- · Led site surveys, studys, data collections and design review meetings with customers. Managed technical team during project
- · Continuously communicated with customer's stakeholders and with our international engineering team.
- Prepared and led the customer witnessed Factory Acceptance tests and site commissioning support.

#### **Control Cabinet Hardware Designer**

GE Oil & Gas | December 2009 - June 2012

Designed Local Control Panels of Mark VIe Gas Turbine Control Systems, Bently Nevada Vibration Monitoring System packages and automation systems following the related international and local standards.

- Created documents, diagrams, loop drawings, schematics in AutoCAD, AutoCAD Electrical, Autodesk Inventor and EPLAN. Managed the Bill of material and Material Masters in ERP (SAP).
- Supported the manufacturing process and the test of the control cabinets. Monitored company inventory to keep stock levels and databases updated.
- · Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.

#### **Manufacturing Support Electrical Engineer**

GE Energy | June 2007 - November 2009

Supported the Areoderivative Gas Turbine power generation package assemblies. Engineer.

#### **Maintenance Electrical/Automation Engineer**

Samsung | October 2003 - May 2007

Installed new equipment and improved the machines on the production line. Made machine trouble analysis and solved the systematical machine breakdowns.

### **Æ PROJECTS**

#### Personal portfolio projects

Personal

I built a couple of projects to demonstrate my technical knowledge. I created smartcoder.dev to present my portfolio.

#### **Meetandworkshop**

Personal

A responsive website created in wordpress for a local co-working office.

#### Statikusvac

Personal

A responsive website created in wordpress for my wife to promote her services.

### **TrueNAS SCALE Server**

Personal

Installed a truenas server in my basement to deploy my personal cloud/data storage, media server and to experiment with other tools/services/containers

## **X** SKILLS **Technical**

JavaScript/React/Redux

React Native

HTML5/CSS/SASS

Node.js/Express.js

MongoDB/SQL

Git

Linux

#### Professional

Effective communication

Team player

Strong problem solver

Adaptability

Decision-making

Technology literacy

### EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Program

CareerFoundry 2022 - present

BSc in Electrical Engineering Budapest Polytechnic 2000 - 2003

#### AT LANGUAGES

English (Professional) Hungarian (Native)

#### (2) INTERESTS

Hikina

Running